Where shall we go this autumn?
And so, after school, I'll be going with
Tani-kun to get a sweet potato parfait!
You're forcing that fall feeling.
I'm happy to go on
a date in our uniforms!
But you two are always walking
home together, aren't you?
No, no.
This is our first time riding
a train together in our uniforms!
We usually walk home together,
yes, but today is a date.
Wait, you're taking a train
just for potatoes?
PotatoTrain.
And while we're out,
if luck is on my side...
I want to take some photo stickers.
IN OUR
UNIFORMS...
FLOWERS IN A MIRROR,
MOON ON THE WATER
A photo sticker printing booth.
When you first started dating,
taking a photo together was impossible.
THIS IS...
GROWTH(?)
Photos take getting used to,
and I've kinda given up, in a way,
but I've always liked
taking photo stickers. Plus...
I'm super cute with all those filters.
PHOTO
STICKER
How dignified and bold.
Don't give up on the real live Suzuki.
YOU AND I ARE POLAR OPPOSITES
Potato! Potato! Sweet potato!
Potato! Potato! Roasted sweet potato!
Oh, hey! Suzuki and Tani
are at the train station.
Hey! Azu!
Oh, my. Could this be one of those
school uniform dates?
How nice for you!
How nice for you...
You said it twice!
For now, let's all take
a picture together.
Yay!
So suddenly?
Tani looks displeased.
What?
No, I don't.
I was wondering why, because we see
each other at school, that's all.
But it's a different situation, right?
It's like a diary entry,
or making a note, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Photos are an external
hard drive for memories!
When I look back at it, I want to remember
that this day was our first date,
that we had a lot of fun, that my
heart was racing... stuff like that.
Like a keepsake. You know?
COMPREHENSION
I see.
Right?
That was enough to convince him?
HOW FUNNY
BOOM
SWEET POTATO!!
Yay! It's so cute!
I'll take one with you in it, Tani-kun.
Make some kind of pose.
A pose?
Hand powers?
This is good!
PRETEND
GOURMET REPORTING
It's super sweet potato-y,
but not too cloying.
It's the sweetness of happiness!
It's so good!
MELTYYYY...
CHOMP...
What? Wait, did you just take a photo?
I just know I was making
a weird face! Oh, no!
I thought we wanted to save
our memories for later.
I don't want any weird photos
of me on your phone.
What? That's so self-centered.
True.
Say, Yuusuke-kun...
CUTESY...
I have one more self-centered request.
BOOM
Look at this one! Isn't it great?
I'm in love with this one!
I want to run away.
Yuusuke-san, have you ever participated
in the act of printing photos as stickers?
I have not.
Are you okay with me picking one?
If one interests you, just say so!
You already know the answer, right?
I guess you caught me.
Okay, let's pose!
Make a heart!
Huh?
Three, two, one!
Make a cute kitty pose!
Kitty?
Three, two, one!
Huh?
Who's that?
Next, grab each others' chins, okay?
What?
Three, two, one!
There!
J-Just kidding!
All right! Now, next...
both of you, smile!
It's so hot.
It's hot in those photo
sticker machines, right?
There's that too, but...
Thank you! I'm super happy!
What should I do with this?
I want to put it up in my room,
but my mom will see it.
STICKER HIDING SPOT
I'll make an album with the
photos and share it with you.
Thanks.
Oh, you added some, Tani-kun?
Thank you!
SHOCK
Wait! Please delete this one!
Don't wanna.
The corrections didn't apply to
Tani-kun at all, did they?
BECAUSE HE
HAS GLASSES...
THE PROCESSING
It's too unbalanced, isn't it?
RAMEN
Manager, thank you.
Thanks!
NO ANSWER
UNREAD MESSAGES BELOW
HOW'VE YOU BEEN? LOL
A blast from the past! He's still alive?
Commentary
They dated for a while, but for some
reason, he suddenly broke off contact.
This message is from an ex-boyfriend!
What's the "lol" for?
Can't he say he's sorry?
Male pride is such a pain.
I guess it doesn't matter.
NO ANSWER
UNREAD MESSAGES BELOW
HOW'VE YOU BEEN? LOL
Doin' Good!
HOW HAVE YOU BEEN?
You know...
If someone you used to know well
messages you after a long time,
your heart brightens for a moment,
but then you notice you don't click
and it all feels like a drag.
And you think, "That's right.
That's why it didn't work out,"
and come back to reality.
How many more times am
I going to repeat this?
GLOOM...
Azu!
I can't sympathize at all.
Why do you let them get away with it?
I don't really get it, but let's
overwrite it with fun stuff!
That straightforwardness
of yours is a lifesaver!
Romance isn't all there is to school life.
That's right!
Let's all go bowling together!
Where'd that come from?
I want to go bowling.
Oh, it's just the mood you're in.
I want to throw something heavy.
I feel like the objective has changed.
WEEKEND
Then, on the weekend...
Azuma says her train's running a little late.
Okay, I'm taking it now.
Yay!
I thought that TairAzuma
would come together.
Don't smash our names
together like they're English.
HO-DON
TAIRAZUMA
But don't you get on at the same station?
You numskull!
If anyone from my neighborhood
saw us meeting up at the station...
Azuma, what's going on?
What caused this particular combo?
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Hey, Azu!
Just thinking about it makes me
break out in a cold sweat.
SHUDDER...
Tani-kun, is this your first time bowling?
I've only bowled once a really
long time ago with a kids' group.
If there's anything you
don't get, I'll teach you!
Incidentally, I hear the shoes are
ugly as an antitheft measure.
Is that vital info?
They're huge.
Everyone, what's your average?
A hundred and eighty!
A hundred and seventy!
A hundred and thirty.
How dare you, Taira.
What?
If I hit a hundred, I feel pretty good.
Same.
And mine's fifty, so...
So you're the worst player.
Now then, I think fifteen should do.
Don't do the Ripper Cyclotron!
Taira, your reactions are so funny.
It makes all the goofing around worth it.
Oh, shut up.
Yeah! Did you see that?
Former classmates from my neighborhood.
They think our neighborhood's the best.
I <3 OUR
NEIGHBORHOOD
They're still all hanging out together?
If I don't look,
maybe they won't notice me.
They wouldn't remember me anyway, right?
But Azuma got along pretty well
with them, didn't she?
I don't want to get involved with
them when I'm with these guys.
Don't worry.
They won't try to talk to you.
What?
I think they'll pretend that
they haven't noticed us.
Not that I really mind, though.
I hope they're happy together.
What are you talking about?
Don't worry about it. Let's have some fun!
Why?
WHOOSH
Tani-kun, that's amazing!
You have a talent for this!
That reaction just for a spare?
Okay! See you later!
See you at school!
It says the next train is in ten minutes.
That's a long time between trains.
It's not likely I'll run into
those guys from earlier, right?
Hey, those guys we saw today...
Weren't you in that same group
back in middle school?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I was, but things
are a little complicated.
So, 1 is my ex.
EX
Another, 2, well, a lot happened,
but it doesn't count.
Doesn't count
And the two girls that were with them
are their current girlfriends, 3 and 4.
What did she just say?
WAS
THAT
JAPANESE?
Huh? What?
So, there was dating and
breaking up in the group,
and you're the ex-girlfriend,
so it's awkward now. Is that right?
Well, I don't mind, personally,
but they seem to feel guilty about it.
When 1 suddenly sent me
a break-up message,
EX
just a little while later,
he started dating 3.
She's calling them by number?
And 2 and I clearly had a good vibe going,
so I wondered why he suddenly ghosted me.
But he was dating 4, and I was like,
"You approached us both at the same time?"
It's all sort of... delicate, you know?
That's absolutely sickening.
I've got massive chills for some reason.
How can they just shuffle partners
within the same community?
Add in the awkwardness that's
created by all of it, and it's just gross.
But actually, when I went
to the bathroom, I ran into 3,
and she was like,
"Oh, hey, long time no see!"
SO IT'S
NOT REALLY
ALL THAT DIRE...
It was pretty easy to just talk normally.
Oh, no, no, no.
You know, that's...
Whoa, 1 just sent something!
UNREAD MESSAGES BELOW
YOU WENT BOWLING
TODAY, RIGHT? LOL
EX (1)
"You went bowling today, right? lol"
...is what he sent.
What? He's shameless.
His intentions are so blatant
that it ends up hilarious, right?
No, no, no.
Get angry!
While we've been talking...
No, actually, before that!
That ex-boyfriend with his sloppy texts...
and that girl who made a calculated
move to act like your friend...
and this guy who might be taking
this opportunity to go after you again...
Not one of them has faced you head-on
or squared things with you!
But none of them have the guts
to just be the bad guy either!
They're way too disrespectful!
You're being treated like trash,
so you should get angry!
You're the only one getting
worn down here, right?
There's no way it's worth it, is there?
But, you know...
Once I like someone, I can't really
bring myself to hate them.
Like, even if stuff happens,
I decide it's fine, and I forgive them.
Oh. That's why they
treat me like trash, right?
So, if you don't hate them,
then you have to just forgive and
accept all their bad parts?
That's not right, is it?
The things that've always nagged at me...
I've never put them into words like
Taira and really thought about them.
I guess it doesn't matter.
Why do you let them get away with it?
Maybe it's not about being treated badly,
or having no luck with men.
Maybe I'm not taking care of myself.
Taira, thanks for yesterday.
Sorry!
Huh?
I'm really sorry about yesterday.
I was so arrogant,
AAAAAAAA...
YESTERDAY'S BAD MOOD TAIRA
and started telling you
what to say to other people.
I pushed my opinion on you.
If it were me, I'd get angry.
I can only talk
because I'm an outsider.
When I see the malignant side of things,
there's this spite in me
that I can't hold back.
It's like a craving to point it all out.
A craving to point it out?
Talking about a theory
might have been okay,
but later I realized how wrong assuming
that I knew what you thought and felt was.
Um, yeah. Okay. I totally get it.
OH, IT'S TAYLAZUMA
GLOOM...
SNEAK
SNEAK...
Well, I guess it's fine.
SNEAK
I forgive you!
Forgive what?!
Hey!
MORNING!
Hey, Miyu.
Your brother and father are both
going to be away this weekend.
WHISPER...
SANDLOT BASEBALL
BROTHER
SLEEPOVER
DAD
Sorry this was so sudden.
Wasn't it sort of far without your bike?
It's supposed to rain today, so...
Oh, is it?
It's just my grandma's intuition, though.
HERE
Oh! Ordering delivery during the
day for a good reason is just so exciting!
YAY
I'm back!
Welcome home! Tani-kun, welcome to...
Um, this is Tani-kun.
Thank you for having me.
He seems like he's been
brought up very well.
SUZUKI'S
OLDER
BROTHER
AND HIS
HOMIES FROM
THE HOOD
THE YOUNG MEN SHE'S SEEN UP UNTIL NOW
Thanks for havin' me!
Hiya, auntie!
Please, right this way.
GULP...
Tani-kun, whereabouts is your house?
The neighborhood next—
Oh, you must be tired
after walking all that way!
Mom, please don't talk over him!
If there's any food you don't like,
you don't have to force yourself.
After all, I'm not the one who made it!
She didn't need to say that last part.
Thank you.
Tani-kun, do you have a favorite food?
Oh! I should have
asked that ahead of time!
If you keep asking questions like that,
he won't be able to eat!
Oh, how rude of me.
SILENCE...
Should I put on some music?
Maybe something like
OFFICIAL HIGE DANSHAKU?
Young people like them, right?
Mom! Please calm down!
I'll bring some snacks up later!
Okay!
Come in. Come in!
I'm sorry. My mom is nervous.
She's nervous?
Yes. By the look of it, very nervous.
I'm not sure I'm saying it right, but she
made me go, "Yes, this is Suzuki's mom."
What? Do you mean that in a good way?
Of course.
Oh! It really did start raining!
I wonder if it'll stop
by the time you go home.
I really like the rain
when I'm inside the house.
I like how it's dark even though it's
daytime, and the sound it makes...
I'm so glad it's raining
for our at-home date!
But our summer break escape-the-heat
study session was great, too!
It's sort of like,
"So you like them both, then?"
SILENCE...
Huh?
Have I been talking too much for too long?
I guess I can't criticize my mom.
And Tani-kun sure is being quiet.
Oh! Um, m-my mom said she'd
bring us some snacks later, so...
So... what about until then?
And what about after that?
Miyu, I brought snacks!
BA-DUMP
I'm home!
Dear?!
Man, the rain made things
rougher than expected,
so the sandlot ballgame got called off.
Wait, wait, wait! Right now, Miyu
has her boy— a guest in her room!
Huh?
I know it's late to realize this, but...
Tani-kun's in my room!
The rain's really coming down, huh?
I hope it stops before you go home.
Yeah.
Uh, did I say that earlier?
What do I do? What should I talk about?
Or should I just be quiet already?
I want to sit over there.
POOF
Um, I...
I... would like... to hug.
I have to be careful
not to get lipstick on him!
WHOA...
DISTRACTING
THOUGHTS
So would I.
Your heartbeat is insane!
ARE YOU
DYING...?!
Please stop.
Honestly! Tani-kun,
you're so hard to read!
When you're not talking,
I don't know what to do.
That's the kind of pathetic
human being I am.
Would you... be all right with that?
That's right.
Tani-kun.
Tani Yuusuke-kun.
What?
Yuusuke-kun. Yuusuke.
I'm just trying out
different things to call you!
YAY
Yuu-kun! Yuu-chan! Suke-san?
You picked that half?
YAY
Miyu-san?
That's so formal!
Miyu-chan?
Whoa! That works!
Miyu.
Sorry, I just can't get used to it.
Yeah.
Oh, that aloha shirt brings back memories!
I thought that this way, even if I bump
into Miyu's friend, I won't embarrass her.
DAD'S VERSION OF STYLISH
Mom!
Tani-kun's heading home,
so I'll go part of the way—
Oh! Um...
This is my boyfriend.
Boyfriend.
What? Boyfriend?! What?!
What's your name?
It's Tani.
No, your first name!
It's Yuusuke.
Yuusuke-kun! Wow! How old are you?
What school do you go to?
Dad! Dad! We'll talk about all that later!
What? But I want to know more!
This is why I really didn't
want them to meet!
AND HIS CLOTHES SEEM TIGHT
FOR SOME REASON...
I'm sorry about my mom and
dad flapping around like that.
And you keep laughing about it! Seriously!
Somehow...
SUZUKI MIYU
things like parents and friendships...
all these different ideas I've had
up to now get turned on their heads.
I was thinking, it's just
who you are, Suzuki-san.
What? That's so embarrassing.
It's like you've read the Suzuki
Kaitai Shinsho, or dissected me like a fish.
Oh! Fall is here!
In the summer, it's so muggy
after the rain stops,
but when it rains closer to autumn,
it really changes the air, doesn't it?
Yeah, it does.
When our middle school culture festival
ended, the temperature was like this,
so now, whenever I feel this, like,
whoosh of air changing,
I always think, "Ah, the culture festival
is done for this year, too."
I feel like I'll probably say
the same thing next year, too.
I think probably...
From now on, whenever I feel
this same atmosphere...
I think I'll remember today.
But that's...
If you say something like that to me...
then I'll end up the same way!
Is that bad?
It's good!
Miyu has a boyfriend?
WOBBLE...
Oh! Please don't drink
alcohol before dinner!